Guide to the Imagining New Orleans Oral History Project Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Imagining New Orleans Oral History Project collection
2005-2006
WA MSS S-2702
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
6.88
(19 boxes)
The collection consists of material created and collected by researchers as part of the Imagining New Orleans Oral History Project. Files consist of digital photographs (on an optical disc), ephemera, printed material, and memorabilia documenting post-Katrina New Orleans in 2006.
Imagining New Orleans Oral History Project
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from the Imagining New Orleans Oral History Project on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 2006.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 11 (optical disc): Restricted Fragile Material. Copies of electronic files are available through Access Services.
Associated Materials
Audio recordings of oral histories are stored at the Southern Oral History Program Collection at the University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, Series U.12.
Imagining New Orleans Oral History Project
In May and June 2006, a team of researchers from the Southern Oral History Program at the University of North Carolina, the New Haven Oral History Project at Yale University, and the Louisiana State Museum created the Imagining New Orleans Oral History Project in order to document the voices of post-Katrina New Orleans residents. The researchers recorded a series of oral histories, created photographs, and collected ephemera, memorabilia and printed material.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of material created and collected by researchers as part of the Imagining New Orleans Oral History Project. Files consist of digital photographs, ephemera, printed material, and memorabilia documenting post-Katrina New Orleans in 2006. An overview in folder 1 describes the project.
Arrangement
Not arranged in any particular order.
Hurricane Katrina, 2005; Hurricane Katrina, 2005 -- Pictorial works; Hurricane Katrina, 2005 -- Social aspects; New Orleans (La.) -- Social conditions -- 21st century; New Orleans (La.) -- Economic conditions -- 21st century; New Orleans (La.) -- Politics and government -- 21st century; Born digital; Digital images; Electronic documents; Imagining New Orleans History Project
- Project overview, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Photographs, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  1 DVD-R optical disc
  Existence and Location of Copies
  Optical disc is restricted. Copies of electronic files are available through Access Services. Disc # 20060717-237.0001.
- Tubby meets Katrina, by Tony Dunbar, printed version, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Spoiled, by Tom Varisco, printed version, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bring New Orleans Back Commission, reports, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Material relating to Echo Olander interview, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Katrina Warriors inaugural event, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Material relating to Vietnamese community, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Material relating to tourism, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Street fliers relating to various topics, including health issues, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Broadmore Improvement Association, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Recovery school district community meeting, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Melon Head cafe, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Election material, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Neighborhood Planning and Community Development Council meeting, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Catholic charities, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Lakeview Welcome Home Workshop, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Material related to Norman Francis interview, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Material related to Dillard University interviews, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Bayou Boogaloo Festival, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
- "Survivor Village," St. Bernard Housing Project, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- F. H. Dunn Resurrection Center, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Marty Rowland, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Material relating to Father Dvorak interview, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Antoinette K-Doe, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Common Ground, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Jerrelyn Jessop Madere, 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- New Orleans Ward and Precinct directory and Mitch Landrieu mayoral campaign material, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 29-32)
- New Orleans Ward and Precinct directory and Mitch Landrieu mayoral campaign material (continued), 2006 (Box 4, Folder 33-37)
- New Orleans Ward and Precinct directory and Mitch Landrieu mayoral campaign material (continued), 2006 (Box 5, Folder 38-43)
- New Orleans Ward and Precinct directory and Mitch Landrieu mayoral campaign material (continued), 2006 (Box 6, Folder 44-48)
- New Orleans Ward and Precinct directory and Mitch Landrieu mayoral campaign material (continued), 2006 (Box 7, Folder 49-54)
- New Orleans Ward and Precinct directory and Mitch Landrieu mayoral campaign material (continued), 2006 (Box 8, Folder 55-59)
- New Orleans Ward and Precinct directory and Mitch Landrieu mayoral campaign material (continued), 2006 (Box 9, Folder 60-65)
- New Orleans Ward and Precinct directory and Mitch Landrieu mayoral campaign material (continued), 2006 (Box 10, Folder 66-69)
- New Orleans Ward and Precinct directory and Mitch Landrieu mayoral campaign material (continued), 2006 (Box 11, Folder 70-74)
- New Orleans Ward and Precinct directory and Mitch Landrieu mayoral campaign material (continued), 2006 (Box 12, Folder 75-80)
- New Orleans Ward and Precinct directory and Mitch Landrieu mayoral campaign material (continued), 2006 (Box 13, Folder 81-85)
- Newspapers, 2006 (Box 14 Oversize, Folder 86-87)
- Newspapers, 2006 (Box 15 Oversize, Folder 88-89)
- Election campaign tee shirts, 2006; (4 items) (Box 16 Oversize)
- Election campaign handkerchief, 2006 (Box 16 Oversize)
- Election campaign sign, 2006 (Box 16 Oversize, Folder 90)
- Beer bottles, glass, 2006; (2 items) (Box 17)
- "Da mayor in your pocket," keychain, 2006 (Box 17)
- Poster, 2006 (Box 18 Oversize, Folder 91)
- Computer media
  - Imagining New Orleans photographs, 2006-wa-237-0001; 1 (Box 19)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - [no label information], 2006-wa-237-0002; 1 (Box 19)
  - Solidarity NOT Charity Common Ground Collective, 2006-wa-237-0003; 1 (Box 19)